## HR CONTACT CENTER SPECIALIST

Summary

Forward-thinking professional with various experience in human resources, sales, customer service and education, offering excellent communication and computer skills; highly organized and meticulous.

Skille

- MS Office Suite
- Self-motivated professional
- Team leadership
- Meeting deadlines
- Time management skills

## Experience

07/2016 to Current

HR Contact Center Specialist Bemidji State University il/4 Bemidji, MN

- Answer and resolve employee and people-manager issues including navigational support and processing corrective transactions when required.
- Provide advice on how to complete requests and/or options for next steps based on scenarios.
- These could include; guidance related to completing HR responsibilities (year- end compensation, mid-year and year-end processes, resource planning), guidance related to making employee data changes (new hires, transfers, terminations, retiring), guidance related to the administration of employee programs (Service recognition, PTO/Vacation entitlement, time administration).
- Maintain adherence to all audit/compliance and regulatory requirements.
- Provide support on all HR policies, processes, and procedures including knowledge of Benefits and Payroll processes and transactions, people-manager responsibilities and employee programs and services (including navigational support of all HR systems) to the employees, people-managers and the HR community.
- In addition to the above duties: I have taken the initiative to be a part of the new hire training, women in leadership and support to my colleagues by helping them improve their metrics and quality of their calls.
- In displaying this leadership, my leadership is providing me the opportunity to be a part of more projects that come down the pipeline.

## 10/2014 to 07/2016

Admissions Representative Charter Spectrum i1/4 Dallas, TX

- Conduct face-to-face or personal interviews, telephone interviews and e-mail correspondence to identify high school and adult student
  prospects to determine their educational needs, concerns and interests.
- Closely assists and mentors students through the Admissions process.
- Ensure compliance with applicable Company policies and procedures, laws and regulations.
- Participates in school retention efforts by maintaining productive contact with his/her active students through graduation.

05/2014 to 10/2014

Recruiting Coordinator

03/2014 to 05/2014

Branch Coordinator Willscot Corporation i1/4 Greensboro, NC

- Conserve database for storage and retrieval of assessments.
- Participate and coordinate (where appropriate) job fairs sponsored by HTI and clients.
- On site coordination of interview activity; run e-verifies, uphold payroll information by collecting, calculating, and entering data.
- Bring up-to-date payroll records by entering changes in exemptions, job title and departments.
- Resolve payroll discrepancies, maintain payroll operations by following policies and procedures and protect payroll operations by keeping information confidential.
- Compile interview packages for exempt and non-exempt; perform criminal background checks and other duties as required in support of the team.
- Maintain and manage all front desk operations.
- Track and monitor branch applicant flow.
- Weekly data entry of all applications received.
- Manage and direct all office traffic.
- Answer and screen all incoming phone calls and transfer as needed.
- Schedule weekly orientations from the candidate pool identified by recruiters.
- Responsible for overall maintenance of the filing systems and other duties as required.

## Education and Training

June 24, 2013

MBA: Business Finance Strayer University i/4 City, State Business 4.0 Graduated with honors Finance

May 7, 2011

Bachelor of Arts : Communication concentration Mass Communication Fayetteville State University  $i\frac{1}{4}$  City , State Communication concentration Mass Communication 3.583 Graduated Magna Cum Laude \*Dean's List

Personal Information

https://www.linkedin.com/in/e-april-bradford-14241955

Activities and Honors

Greenville Society for Human Resource Management (GSHRM) (2015-2016) Society for Human Resource Management (SHRM) (2015-2016) Treasurer/Guardian of chapter's funds/Chair of Budget and Finance Committee-Pi Zeta Omega Chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Inc. (2014) Alpha Chi National Honor Scholarship Society (2013-2015) Golden Key International Honour Society (2012-2015) Golden Key International Honour Society Education and Literacy service director (2012) Connections Committee chair- Delta Alpha Chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority Inc. (2010-2011) Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority Inc. (2010-2011) Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority Inc. 2010-present: Delta Alpha chapter (2010-2011) Pi Zeta Omega Chapter (2013-2014)

Skills

Benefits, Interpersonal skills, clients, data entry, database, e-mail, filing, HR, leadership, Team leadership, MS Office Suite, office, Multi-tasking, next, Payroll, policies, processes, quality, Recruitment, Self-motivated, Staffing, telephone, telephone etiquette, phone, Time management, year-end, year-end

Additional Information

• Additional Information \*https://www.linkedin.com/in/e-april-bradford-14241955